# Roberto Serra

# Full Stack Senior Engineer

e: obi.serra@gmail.com
g: https://github.com/obiSerra
l: https://www.linkedin.com/in/obiserra/
w: https://www.rserra.it/

## Summary

I am a software developer with almost 15 years of experience; during those years I worked as a freelance, consultant and employee, having the opportunity to work with startups as well as creatives collective and enterprise companies

# Work Experiences

## Tech Lead and Senior Software Engineer

Sept 2014 - Present

Designing and developing enterprise and large scale modern web applications for the US and European markets.

### Web and Mobile Developer

Jan 2012 - Aug 2014

Developing and designing web applications, mobile apps (PhoneGap and Titanium) and HTML5 games.

### Co-founder and Developer

Mar 2010 - Dec 2011

Developing web sites and web applications for small and medium sized companies

#### Web Developer

Mar 2010 - Dec 2011

Developing and maintaining a live auction web application

# Notable Projects

## Solution Architect and Team Lead for San Francisco based startup

Through my dual responsibilities as a Solution Architect and Team Leader, I coordinated the efforts of the engineering team, driving them towards the successful delivery of an ad-hoc solution that met the client's requirements.

As a Solution Architect, I actively participated in meetings with the startup CEO, my US team counterpart, and other stakeholders to collaboratively design both locally hosted and cloud-based solutions.

Additionally, as a Team Leader, I employed Agile methodologies to guide and support my team throughout the development process. This involved reviewing Pull Requests, facilitating Test Driving Development, and writing code in Python and TypeScript.

Tech: Python, AWS, React, Typescript, Software architecture, TDD, Agile, Scrum

#### Senior full-stack developer for a worldwide sport event

During my tenure, I contributed to the development of the primary website for a prestigious global sports event scheduled for 2020 (subsequently postponed to 2021).

Initially, I joined as a senior frontend developer, where I played a crucial role in integrating third-party news feeds, advertising elements, and a multimedia gallery as well providing assistance to fellow team members.

As my responsibilities expanded, I began working on the backend as well, implemented new website sections, optimizing the indexing and search engine capabilities within the client's proprietary framework.

Tech: C#, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

#### Full-stack developer for a US assurance company

I worked as full-stack developer on a insurance quoting web application targeted to medium and small business for a Fortune top 10 assurance company, refactoring an old Java monolith application into a micro-services based one, using Clojure, RabbitMQ and Jenkins to increase the maintanibility and the ease of deploy; we also created an ad-hoc git flow to better manage the project.

Tech: Clojure, JavaScript, RabbitMQ, Jenkins, AngularJs

#### Interactive YouTube Masthead for an italian fashion brand

I created an engaging YouTube Masthead that featured an interactive element. This unique masthead presented two versions of the same commercial simultaneously, with one playing on the top half and the other on the bottom. To provide an interactive experience, I implemented a draggable divider line that allowed users to select which video and music they wanted to watch simply by dragging it up and down.

Tech: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Canvas

# Other Projects

- Taught a NodeJs laboratory at Turin University for 2 years
- Several car configurators for top a multinational automotive company
- A management tool for massive live tournaments for a US gaming company
- Two multi-platform mobile applications
- A real time auction web application
- Partecipated to many code challenges such as Js13K, Google Hashcode, Google FooBar

# Key Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, ClojureScript Python, Clojure, C#, PHP, Bash Script React, NodeJs, Vue.js, Express.js

Pandas, Pytorch, Unity, Unity ML-Agents, Prompt Engineering

DynamoDb, MongoDb, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Lambda, S3, CloudFormation, Cognito, APIGateway, Google Cloud Provider

Git, bash, ssh, MacOS, Linux, Jenkins

Great attitude to work with teams and as team leader Good expirience as Solution Design and Tech Lead

# Other interests

- Al and Machine Learning enthusiast
- Reinforcement Learning applied to board games (Connect 4, Chess) and Unity custom environments
- Kaggle ML competitions
- Algorithms, Coding competitions

#### Education

## Università degli Studi di Torino

Laurea in Scienze Della Comunicazione - Bachelor of Arts in Communication Studies